chevroncars.com 2007-12-27

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy for Kids Under 13 and Their Parents

_(Please see below forPrivacy Policy for Everyone Over 13)_

Welcome to the Chevron Cars website!! We are about to tell you some very important information, so please ask your mom or dad to come and read along with you. We are very concerned about protecting the privacy of children under 13. So, we think that it's important for you and your parents to understand and feel comfortable with how we collect information from you and how we use that information. 

The Chevron Cars website is designed for kids of all ages to play games, have fun, and learn new things. We have packed our site with lots of different games, activities, and an online store called the KIDS SHOP. We hope that you'll look around the KIDS SHOP at all of the cool things, but you can't buy anything in the KIDS SHOP unless you are 18 years or older. If you are under 18 and you want to buy something, you'll have to ask your parents to buy it for you. 

We are not allowed to require you to tell us more about yourself than is reasonably necessary to play games or participate in activities on our site. So, for most activities, we don't ask you for any identifying information. For some activities, we ask for your email address and your parent's email address. We only ask for your email address when you ask US to send YOU email, such as a newsletter or an answer to your question. We also ask for your email when you send an electronic postcard or use the "email this page" button to a friend, but we delete this email immediately after the email is sent and do not store it. And, we ask for your parent's email address so that we can tell your mom or dad that you have asked us to send you email. We don't share any information collected on this site with anybody. And, as you'll see, there are no advertisers on this site. 

See this cute squirrel? 

That's Wally the Warning Squirrel. He will appear to warn you that either (1) you are being asked to give us personally identifying information, (2) you are entering an area of the site that contains commercial and/or product information, or (3) you are entering the KIDS SHOP where you must be 18 or older and have a valid credit card to make a purchase. 

#### Privacy Policy Table Of Contents:

  * WHAT information we collect and WHY we collect it
  * Reviewing or changing your information
  * Links to other sites
  * How to contact us

##### WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHY WE COLLECT IT:

Here is the scoop on HOW and WHEN we ask for information, WHAT information we collect and WHY we collect it: 

**(1)Information for Registration.** To save your personal game scores in the PLAYGROUND or to make a wish list in the KIDS SHOP we ask you to register. To register, we ask you for two pieces of information about you: your birthday and parent's email address. We also ask you for a Screen Name and Password that you get to choose. NONE of this information, by itself or in combination, is enough to tell us who you are or how to contact you, except through your parent's email address. 

**_YOUR BIRTHDAY._** We use your birthday to see how many people in your age group are using the site, and we use that information to improve the site. 

**_YOUR PARENT'S EMAIL._** If you are under 13, we ask you for your parent's email address. We use your parent's email address only as a means to notify your mom or dad that you have registered on our site. 

**_A SCREEN NAME AND PASSWORD YOU CHOOSE._** The Screen Name and Password you choose should be a favorite hobby, a favorite animal, your favorite food, or any other neat word. To better protect your privacy, we specifically ask you NOT to use your real name for your Screen Name or your Password. You should be careful in maintaining the confidentiality and security of your User Name and Password. Notwithstanding our security measures, the nature of the Internet and each user's computer and/or other access device all permit the possibility that your data and your computer and/or other access device are potentially accessible by third parties, such as computer hackers. 

**(2) The Kids Shop.** Everyone is allowed to browse the KIDS SHOP and look at all the cool things for sale. BUT you MUST BE 18 OR OLDER and have a valid credit card to make a purchase. If you want to, you can make a "Wish List" of the cool things you like in the KIDS SHOP and send it in an email to your friends and family!! If you want to make and save a "Wish List" in the KIDS SHOP, you first will have to make sure that you have logged in with your Screen Name and Password. Once you are logged in, just click on the "Add to Wish List" button on any of the pages that feature a car or product and that item will be added to your "Wish List." You can view and edit your "Wish List" whenever you come back to the KIDS SHOP. To view it, simply make sure you are logged in and click on the Wish List icon at the top right hand of any page in the KIDS SHOP. Your Wish List will appear and you will be able to view and delete any of the items on your Wish List. If you want to, you can email your "Wish List" to friends and family. When you send your "Wish List", we don't save either your email address or your friend's email address. The "Wish List" is sent from YOUR email address, NOT from our website address. 

**(3) Newsletters.** If you decide that you want to, you can ask to receive a subscription to one of our newsletters via email. Just click on the "Sign Up" button under the Newsletters/Subscribe section on the homepage, or elsewhere on the site. When you click on the Newsletter "Sign Up" button after having entered your email address, we ask you to tell us how old you are on the Registration Page. After you tell us your age, and if you are below 13, a new page appears and asks for your parent's email address. We keep your parent's email address so that your parent can review, change, delete or block your email address from our newsletter mailing list at any time. We keep your email address only so that we can send you newsletters and only for as long as you want us to keep sending them to you. If or when you decide that you don't want to receive a newsletter anymore, just reply to any newsletter, put "unsubscribe" in the subject line and we will stop sending it to you and delete your email address from our mailing list for that newsletter. 

If you are under 13 years of age, and do not register on the Registration page, or if your birthdate as entered is not valid for any reason, we treat your email address as we would the email address of anyone under 13, and keep it completely separate from your profile or any personally identifiable information. Similarly, if you sign-up for a newsletter and are already logged in or registered as someone under 13, your email address is kept completely separate from your profile and any personally identifiable information. 

We have two newsletters that you may subscribe to: THE TRIBUNE, and GENERAL TOY CAR NEWS. THE TRIBUNE is a weekly newsletter about fun things to do, interesting historical events, and little known facts. GENERAL TOY CAR NEWS is a note about new games and content on the website, and news about the toy cars. Remember, we won't send a newsletter to you automatically -- you have to tell us that you want to receive it. 

**(4) My Cars.** If you have a collection of Chevron Cars at home, you can go to MY CARS and make a list of your collection online so that you can keep track of which cars you own. If you want to build and save your online collection, just make sure that you are logged in and click on the "MY CARS" icon that appears at the top of every page of the website. When you get into MY CARS, you can add all of the cars you own and save the list. Just click on the "Add to my Collection" button and click on the car that you would like to add. You can also officially register each of your cars. If you decide to officially register one of your cars you will be asked the following questions: 

  * How did you acquire the car?
  * Where did you purchase the car?
  * When did you get your car?
  * How did you learn about this car?
  * What is your first name (so that we can display it on the certificate)?
  * Did you receive this car as a gift? If so, what is the first name of the person who gave it to you (so that we can display it on the certificate)?
  * How many of this car do you have?
  * You can also add personal notes about your car.

None of the information that you tell us in MY CARS, by itself or in combination, is enough to tell us who you are or how to contact you. When you've finished, you can print your online collection, you can print your official certificate, or you can email your online collection to your friends or family. When you email your online collection to your friends or family, we do not save either your email address or your friend's email address. Your collection is sent from YOUR email address, NOT from our website address. 

**(5) Winning a Prize.** From time to time, we sponsor contests online in which you will have the chance to win a prize. If you win one of the contests, we will post a message in the section that you entered the contest like Answering Machine or Know-It-All. In order to know if you are a winner and to get this message, you must be logged on to the site under your User Name. Then, we will ask you to send us your parent's email address so that we can send an email to your parent to let your mom or dad know that you have won a prize on our website. We will also tell your mom or dad what he or she needs to do to help you claim your prize. We will only use personal information about you that we collect from your mom or dad for the purpose of sending you the prize and we will delete your personal information from our records immediately after sending you the prize. 

**(6) Questions and Feedback.** As you look at our site, you might decide to use our feedback page to give us advice about what you think we are doing well, or what you think we can do to make this website even better. If you want to give us feedback, you may do so on the homepage or in the FREE STUFF section without telling us anything about yourself. But, if you ask a question and would like us to respond, you will need to give us your email address. We will use your email address ONLY to respond to the question or feedback that you sent to us, and then we will throw your email address away. 

**(7) Cookies and Other Electronic Footprints.** Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies let us know if you come back to Chevron Cars, so that we can say, "Hello, again" and they help us keep track of your High Score on the games you play!!! You can set your browser to refuse cookies if you want to, but it might interfere with some of your activities on the site. 

When you are surfing the different pages on our website, your electronic footprints allow our computer to identify your computer using its IP address. Using the IP address, our computer gathers certain information such as which pages you visited and how long you stayed. But NONE of this information gives us access to your name, where you live, your email or other personally identifiable information. We use this anonymous information to help us figure out what you like most about our site so that we can keep improving it for everyone to enjoy!! 

**(8) Electronic Postcards and "Email this page" button.** When you send an electronic postcard to a friend or use the "email this page" button to send a link to a friend, we ask for your email address so that the person who receives the email knows who the email is from. We do not however store your or your friend's email, and delete it immediately after sending the message. When your friend views the postcard you sent them on the site, they cannot see your email address. 

Back to Top

##### REVIEWING OR CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION

**GAMES AND ACTIVITIES:** If you want to view, change or delete the information that you gave us to save your scores in the PLAYGROUND or to make a "Wish List" in the KIDS SHOP, such as your Password or birthday you can do so by clicking on the "My Profile" icon that will appear in the top left corner of every page. When you click on the "My Profile" icon, you will be asked to enter your password. Then, the form that you filled out when you registered will appear. You may make whatever changes you would like. When you are finished, press the "Update" button to save your changes. You can change or delete your information at any time. If your mom or dad wants to change or delete your profile, they can do so at any time by sending us an email with your Screen Name and Password to [privacy2@chevroncars.com](mailto:privacy2@chevroncars.com). 

**NEWSLETTERS:** If you want to review or change any information that you gave us to receive a Newsletter, you may do so by clicking on the "Edit My Subscription" on the bottom of each newsletter. This will take you to the website where you may alter your email address or unsubscribe from any or both newsletters. The link is coded so that only the recipient of the email can come to the "Edit My Subscription" page. If you want to cancel your subscription to a Newsletter, you may also do so by replying to one of the newsletters and inserting "unsubscribe" in the subject line. If you cancel all subscriptions, we will delete your email address. If your mom or dad wants to block your Newsletter subscriptions, he or she can send an email with "Data Collection Block" in the subject line to [privacy2@chevroncars.com](mailto:privacy2@chevroncars.com). We will then delete all of your information EXCEPT your parent's email address, which we will keep. If your mom or dad has blocked your subscriptions and you try to re-subscribe, we will block our collection of any information from you when you enter your parent's email address. We will then send your mom or dad an email telling them that you have been back to our site. If your mom or dad decides it's okay for you to subscribe again, they can send an email to profile2@chevroncars.com to tell us to let you subscribe again. Finally, if we ever find that we mistakenly have collected information that under this Privacy Policy we said we wouldn't be collecting, we will delete that information from our records immediately. 

**MY CARS:** To view or edit your online collection in MY CARS, just make sure you are logged in and click on the MY CARS button at the top of any page on the website. Your online collection will appear and you will be able to view, add, register or change information about a car, add a new car or delete a car from your collection. If you want to unsubscribe from MY CARS completely, just send an email to profile2@chevroncars.com and put "REMOVE from MY CARS" in the subject line. 

Back to Top

##### LINKS TO OTHER SITES

We provide links to other websites on some sections of our site because we think they provide activities and offers that you might enjoy. To help you tell whether you are on our site or another company's site, we display warnings to let you know you are leaving our site and entering another. Once you enter the other site, if you use any of their services or provide them with any information, THEIR rules and policies apply, not ours. 

You should be careful not to provide any personal information, such as your name, address, or email address to other websites unless the privacy policy specifies a way for your parents to give permission, and your parents do give you permission to participate on the site. 

Back to Top

##### HOW TO CONTACT US

This site is managed on behalf of Chevron Products Company, a division of Chevron U.S.A. Inc., by ISL Consulting. Chevron Products Company and ISL Consulting are both "operators" of this site. ISL Consulting is the custodian of all records that relate to this website. Chevron is responsible for this privacy policy. If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, the Chevroncars.com website, the KIDS SHOP, or purchases made in the KIDS SHOP, you can contact ISL Consulting at: 

**ISL Consulting**  
944 Market Street, 6th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94102  
(415)981-5000  

Back to Top

##### LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

IN NO EVENT WILL CHEVRON OR ISL CONSULTING BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER ARISING OUT OF THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, OR ANY WEB SITES LINKED TO OUR SITE, THE MATERIALS OR INFORMATION CONTAINED AT ANY OR ALL SUCH SITES, OR THE MATERIALS, PRODUCTS OR SERVICES OFFERED ON THIS SITE OR SITES LINKED TO THIS SITE, WHETHER BASED ON WARRANTY, CONTRACT, TORT OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY AND WHETHER OR NOT ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. 

##### REVISIONS TO THESE TERMS OF USE

Chevron may at any time revise this Privacy Policy by updating this posting. By using this website, you agree to be bound by any such revisions and should therefore periodically visit this page of the website to determine the then current Privacy Policy to which you are bound. Certain provisions of these Privacy Policy may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms located on particular pages on this website. 

### Privacy Policy for Everyone Over 13 Years Old

_(Please see above forPrivacy Policy for Kids Under 13 and Their Parents)_

Welcome to the Chevron Cars website!! Because we respect your privacy, we want to disclose to you how we use the information that you provide to us online. Most of our site is intended for children's use, and in our Privacy Policy for Kids, we tell kids and their parents about our collection and use of information from children under 13. 

The Chevron Cars website is designed for kids of all ages to play games, have fun, and learn new things. We have designed our site to include games, activities and an online store called the KIDS SHOP. The KIDS SHOP contains items we know are attractive to children and teenagers under 18, but we do not allow anyone under 18 years old to make a purchase in the store. Of course, we encourage people of all ages to look at our cool merchandise. However, we make it very clear to all users that you must be 18 or older to make a purchase in our KIDS SHOP. In fact, you can't make a purchase in the KIDS SHOP without a valid credit card. Anybody under 18 wanting to make a purchase must ask their parents to do it for them. 

#### Privacy Policy Table Of Contents:

  * WHAT information we collect and How we use that information
  * Reviewing or changing your information
  * Links to other sites
  * How to contact us

##### WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE THAT INFORMATION:

Following is a list of the kinds of information we collect on our site, and how we use that information. 

**(1) Cookies and Other Electronic Footprints.** Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. The cookies used on this site are used for games and activities, so that we can keep track of scores and welcome users back to play more games. If you set your browser to decline cookies, you may find that some parts of the site will not function properly. 

When you are surfing the different pages on our website, your electronic footprints allow our computer to identify your computer using its IP address. Using your IP address, our computer gathers certain information such as which pages you visited and how long you stayed. But, the information that we obtain from your IP address does not allow us to access to any of your identifying information. We use this anonymous information to help us determine which areas of our site people are visiting most so that we can make appropriate improvements to the site. 

**(2) The Kids Shop.** You may enter the KIDS SHOP and look at all of our great merchandise. But, if you want to make and save a Wish List or make a purchase, we ask you first to log in. If you have already registered in another section of the website, the same Screen Name and Password will allow you to log in at the KIDS SHOP. If you haven't previously registered on the website, we ask you to register in the KIDS SHOP. To register, we ask you to create a profile using a Screen Name, a Password, and your birth date. 

If you are 18 or older and are logged in with a Screen Name, we collect additional information from you in the KIDS SHOP when you make a purchase. We will ask for your actual name, address, credit card number, telephone number, email address and birth date. We need all of this information to sell you the item and to ship it to where you live. Upon completion of the transaction, we will store all of this information EXCEPT for your credit card number. If you input this additional information and your credit card number is invalid, we will store everything EXCEPT the invalid credit card number. We do not disclose any of the information that you provide to us in the KIDS SHOP to anybody else. 

Our site makes it possible to create and email a "Wish List" of the things you like in the KIDS SHOP to your friends and family. When you send your "Wish List" to your friends, we do not store your email address or your friend's email address. The "Wish List" is sent using your personal email address, not our website address. Your "Wish List" will not be saved unless you are logged in when you make your "Wish List." If you are logged in when you make your "Wish List", we will save it for you so you can see it the next time you visit. 

There are no advertisers on our site collecting information about you, and we do not sell our customer lists to anybody. If this policy changes, you will be notified on this site, and you will have the option to request that we not disclose your information. 

**(3) Games, Newsletters, and Activities.** We do not request any personally identifying information to play any of the games and activities on the Chevron Cars site (excluding the Newsletters and Feedback). If you haven't already been to the KIDS SHOP, you will be asked to create a profile by choosing a Screen Name and a Password and entering your birthday to participate in games and activities. If you are 13 to 17, you will have the option to sign up to receive email from the KIDS SHOP that will give you information on new products and promotions but you will not be able to order from the site unless you are 18 or older. If you do sign up to receive email from the KIDS SHOP, you should enter your email address in the space provided and we will store your email address along with the rest of your profile. If you do not sign up to receive email from the KIDS SHOP, you may enter your email address in the space provided but it is not required. If you want to sign up for our Newsletters: GENERAL TOY CAR NEWS and THE TRIBUNE, you may do so by clicking on the Newsletters/Subscribe "Sign Up" button on the homepage or elsewhere on the website. There you can enter your email address in the space provided, and When when you click on the Newsletter "Sign Up" button, we ask you to tell us your age if you are not already registered and are not logged in. If you are not registered, and choose to skip this page, then we treat your email address as we do anyone under the age of 13 and keep it completely separate from any personally identifiable information. If you do register and are above the age of 13, we associate your email address with your profile and you can edit it through the My Profile tab on the site. You may also unsubscribe from any newsletter or modify your email address by pressing the "Edit My Subscription" button at the bottom of each newsletter, or reply to any newsletter and put the word 'unsubscribe" in the subject line. 

You can build an online collection of the Chevron Cars that you own and officially register each of your cars in MY CARS. Remember that your online collection will not be saved unless you are logged in when you build your online collection. You can also print your online collection, print any of your registration certificates, or you can email your online collection to your friends. When you email your online collection to your friends, we do not store your email address or your friend's email address. Your online collection is sent using your personal email address, not our website address. 

From time to time, we sponsor contests online in which you will have the chance to win a prize! If you win one of the contests, we will post a message in the section that you entered the contest like Answering Machine or Know-It-All. In order to know if you are a winner and to get this message, you must be logged on to the site under your User Name. We will also ask you for your email address so that we can send you an email with instructions on how to claim the prize. This email will include a toll-free phone number that you will need to call to claim your prize. On the telephone, we will have to ask you for your name and your mailing address so that we can send the prize to you. We will only use your name and mailing address for the purpose of sending you the prize and we will delete your name and mailing address from our records immediately after sending you the prize. 

When you send an electronic postcard to a friend, or use the "email this page" button to send a link to a friend, we ask for your email address so that the person who receives the email knows who the email is from. We do not however store your or your friend's email, and delete it immediately after sending the message. When your friend views the postcard you sent them on the site, they cannot see your email address. 

If we send you an answer to your feedback or a question, we will delete your email address immediately after we respond. We do not share your email address or any of the other information we collect with third parties. Should this policy change, we will post a notice on our site and provide you with the option to keep your information private. 

Back to Top

##### REVIEWING OR CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION

**GAMES AND ACTIVITIES:** If you want to change or delete any of your log on information, such as your Password or birthday, click on the "My Profile" Icon located in the top right corner of every page. 

**NEWSLETTERS:** If you want to review, change, delete or block any information that you gave us to subscribe to a Newsletter, you can do it by clicking on the "Sign Up" button under the Newsletters section on the homepage. Then, click on the link that allows you to modify the information you submitted to sign up for a newsletter. Your Newsletter profile will appear and you can cancel your subscription by clicking on the boxes in front of the Newletter(s) you no longer wish to receive to remove the mark in the box. Once the mark is removed, you will be deleted from our list of recipients for that Newsletter. When you have finished, press "Save Changes" to save your changes. If you opt not to receive ANY Newsletters, you may press the "Delete My Registration" button and your email address will be deleted from our records. 

If you decide that you no longer wish to receive email from the Kids Shop with product information and promotions, just click on the "My Profile." If you are not already logged in, you will be asked to enter your Password. After you have entered your Password, your profile will appear. Click on the "Edit my profile" link and all of the information you input into your profile will appear. You may then unsubscribe to the Kids Shop email by changing your response to the question "From time to time, Chevron Cars would like to send you email messages on new products or promotions. Would you like to receive this email?" from "yes" to "no." You may also delete your email address in the space provided if you wish. 

**KIDS SHOP:** If you have made a purchase in the KIDS SHOP and you want to review, change or delete the information you submitted to make a purchase in the KIDS SHOP, such as your name, address, email address and telephone number, you may do so by clicking on the My Profile icon. Before you can access your profile and log on information, we ask you to provide your Password to protect your privacy. In My Profile you will also have access to the other information you provided to log on to the website, such as your Password. You may then make whatever changes you would like and press the "Update" button to confirm the changes. Since you are already logged in, you can continue your shopping and purchase process if you'd like. 

**MY CARS:** If you want to view or edit your online collection in MY CARS, just make sure you are logged in and click on the MY CARS button at the top of any page on the website. Your online collection will appear and you can view, add, delete or change information about a particular car. You can also add or delete cars from your collection. If you want to unsubscribe from MY CARS completely, just send an email to profile2@chevroncars.com and put "REMOVE from MY CARS" in the subject line. 

Back to Top

##### LINKS TO OTHER SITES

We provide links to other websites on some sections of our site because we think they provide activities and offers that you might enjoy. To help you distinguish between our site and the other companies' sites, we display warnings to let you know you are leaving our site and entering another. Once you enter the third party site, your use of their services and the information that you provide to them is subject to their rules and policies, not ours. 

Back to Top

##### HOW TO CONTACT US

This site is managed on behalf of Chevron Products Company, a division of Chevron U.S.A. Inc., by ISL Consulting. Chevron Products Company and ISL Consulting are both "operators" of this site. ISL Consulting is the custodian of all records that relate to the KIDS SHOP. Chevron is responsible for this privacy policy. If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, the KIDS SHOP, or purchases made in the KIDS SHOP, you can contact ISL Consulting at: 

**ISL Consulting**   
944 Market Street, 6th Floor   
San Francisco, CA 94102   
(415)981-5000   

Back to Top

##### LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

IN NO EVENT WILL CHEVRON OR ISL CONSULTING BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER ARISING OUT OF THE USE, INABILITY TO USE, OR ANY WEB SITES LINKED TO OUR SITE, THE MATERIALS OR INFORMATION CONTAINED AT ANY OR ALL SUCH SITES, OR THE MATERIALS, PRODUCTS OR SERVICES OFFERED ON THIS SITE OR SITES LINKED TO THIS SITE, WHETHER BASED ON WARRANTY, CONTRACT, TORT OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY AND WHETHER OR NOT ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. 

##### REVISIONS TO THESE TERMS OF USE

Chevron may at any time revise this Privacy Policy by updating this posting. By using this website, you agree to be bound by any such revisions and should therefore periodically visit this page of the website to determine the then current Privacy Policy to which you are bound. Certain provisions of these Privacy Policy may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms located on particular pages on this website. 

Back to Top
